The Teiko Middle School basketball club.
（ナレーション）帝光(ていこう)中学校
バスケットボール部
An incredibly strong team with over one hundred members and three consecutive championship wins.
部員数は100を超え
全中三連覇を誇る 超強豪校
Even within that brilliant history,
その輝かしい歴史の中でも
特に“最強”と呼ばれ—
a group of five prodigies known as the
"Generation of Miracles" stood above the rest.
無敗を誇った10年に１人の天才が
５人同時にいた世代は—
“キセキの世代”と言われている
が “キセキの世代”には
奇妙なうわさがあった
However, there was a strange rumor concerning the Generation of Miracles.
Despite being relatively unknown
誰も知らない 試合記録もない
and lacking a game record,
there was one more member
recognized by the five prodigies.
にもかかわらず—
天才５人が 一目置いていた
選手がもう１人
A phantom sixth man.
幻のシックスマンがいた と
Let's fly now.
Author        Tadatoshi Fujimaki
Published in Shounen Jump
Let's try now.
Let's
fly
now.
Get
my
stage!
Let's
try
now.
Next
my
stage!
Let's
fly
now.
Translation Check   AMS
Get
my
stage!
Let's
fly
now.
Now!
Running into the middle of that exciting stage...
mu
ne
o
do
ru
su
tee
ji
e
ka
ke
a
ga
ru
do
ma
nna
ka
de
K-Timing      Eternal Blizzard
Editing      AMS
Continually breakthrough your limits.
ka
gi
ri
na
ku
ri
n
ka
i
te
n
to
ppa
mi
se
te
yo
Timing       ninjacloud
We have dreams, we're fond of legends, everybody in the ring.
yu
me
ta
shi
na
mu
re
je
n
do
every
body
wa
no
na
ka
de
Don't hesitate, into the future, JUMP!
ma
yo
i
na
ku
mi
ra
i
e
no
JUMP
Typesetting      KmE, zegond
They all say they haven't fallen after they have.
o
chi
bu
re
te
na
i
to
o
chi
bu
re
te
ka
ra
i
u
ya
tsu
ba
kka
It's scary aiming at coming back from the dead but
ki
shi
ka
i
se
ne
ra
u
mi
chi
no
ri
ko
wa
ku
na
wa
i
ga
QC      muyg, sangofe,
ninjacloud
if the road is still blocked
ko
e
te
ku
ka
be
na
no
ni
tsu
u
ka
te
n
na
no
ni
Karaokes      KmE
after I've crossed all the barriers,
fu
sa
i
de
ru
na
ra
I need to realize I'm not alone.
hi
to
ri
ja
na
i
ji
ka
ku
o
Slam it!
t
o
d
k
e
We have to set the rim on fire!
w
e
h
a
v
e
t
o
m
a
k
e
a
R
I
M
F
I
R
E
Let's combine our power and our minds.
a
w
s
e
r
o
p
w
e
r
n
o
a
k
n
o
m
i
n
d
Encoding      Your Mom
We don't need any excuses.
i
w
a
k
e
i
r
a
n
z
o
Gotta dream, exceed your limits, and war.
G
o
t
a
d
r
e
a
m
g
e
n
k
a
i
t
o
w
a
r
I need to face up to my common sense,
ta
chi
ha
da
ka
ru
no
wa
ri
ka
i
shi
su
gi
ta
Kuroko's
I
(
)
I
(
)
Basketball
joushiki to
which I know all too well,
kodoku no maibotsu
and bury my loneliness.
RIM
FIRE!!
Come visit us at www.saizen-fansubs.com
（青峰(あおみね)）そうそう
張り切ってくれよ
That's it, show some spirit
（火神(かがみ)）なっ！
so you can entertain me a little.
（青峰）少しでも オレを
楽しませられるようにさ
A fadeaway?
（伊月）フェイダウェイ！？
（火神）ええいっ！ くそっ！
ダメか！？
Damn it. I can't keep up.
This guy...
（青峰）こいつ！
ハッ やめだ
Enough.
Honest basketball just isn't for me.
やっぱ性に合わねーわ
生真面目なバスケは
No! Those unconventional tricky movements...
（火神）違う！ 型にはまらない
トリッキーな動き…
ストリートのバスケだ！
It's street ball!
No you don't!
（日向(ひゅうが)）させっかあ！！
Episode 18
No!!
（観客）うわっ！
ゴールと全然違うほうへ跳んだ！？
He's going away from the hoop!
What is he thinking?
You can't get past me!
（火神）抜けてねえぞ！！
There isn't a shot you can make from that position!
そんな体勢で打てるシュートは
ねえだろ！
What was that shot?
（河原(かわはら)）なんだ 今のシュート！？
Not a jump shot, but a hook?
（降旗(ふりはた)）ジャンプシュート
じゃなくて フック…！？
In all sports, including basketball,
（緑間(みどりま)）バスケットに限らず
どんなスポーツでも—
fundamental movements and the ideal form have been polished throughout the sport's history.
その歴史の中で洗練されてきた
基本の動きがあり—
理想のフォームがあるのだよ
Because they have been refined to perfection, their options are limited and can be predicted.
洗練され
ムダがなくなったからこそ—
選択肢は限られ
逆に予測も成り立つ
This sets the stage for the strategic battle between the offense and defense.
そこにオフェンス
ディフェンスの—
駆け引きが生まれる
That is the game.
それがゲームだ
But he...
だが あいつは…
He's been handling a basketball since before I can remember.
（さつき）物心つく前から
バスケットボールに触れ—
He was always playing on the street with adults.
大人に混じり ストリートで
ずっとプレーしてきた
ボールハンドリング プラス
天性のスピード
His ball handling plus his natural speed...
A free-spirited style.
自由奔放なバスケットスタイル
There is no form to Aomine's dribbling or shooting.
（緑間）ドリブルもシュートも
青峰の動きに型はない
He is limitless, impossible to defend against.
無限！！
ゆえに ディフェンス不可能
アンストッパブル･スコアラー
He is the unstoppable scorer.
それが
“キセキの世代”のエース—
The ace of the Generation of Miracles:
Aomine Daiki.
青峰大輝(だいき)
（日向）なんだこいつ
スキだらけじゃ…！？
What's with this guy?
His play is full of gaps.
（日向）うぐっ！？
Crap! It's an irregular change of pace!
（日向）やっべ！ 変則の
チェンジオブペースかよっ！！
You bastard...
っのやろぉ！
（緑間）今までより一段と…
（黄瀬(きせ)）高い！
He's jumping even...
higher!
（１年生たち）
止めてくれ 火神〜！！
You can do it, Kagami!
あ〜 はいはい
確かに高(たけ)えよ 大したモンだ
Yeah, yeah. You can jump high.
Good for you.
But I'm tired of this.
けど もう飽きたわ
W-What was that?
（伊月(いづき)）な… なんだそれ！？
He scored with his body almost parallel to the ground!
上体をほとんど
寝かせながら打ってきた？！
Usually the best players shoot at a consistent height,
（日向）
普通 シュートってのは—
上手いヤツほど
ループの高さがいつも変わらない
but he's all over the place.
けど あいつはてんでバラバラだ
なのに 落ちない
And he doesn't miss!
Damn it, I can't predict what he's going to do next!
（火神）くそおっ
次 何してくるか
まったく読めねえ！！
I'll just have to score more than him!
だったら 取られる以上に
点 取ってやる！！
If I can't beat him with speed,
平面の速さで
勝てねえんだったら—
I'll beat him with height!
高さで勝負だ！
If he can't reach me, he can't stop me!
届かなきゃ 止められねえだろ！
Sorry.
わりいな ノロすぎて
つい とっちまったわ
You're so slow I took the ball.
待て コラッ！！
Get back here!
（観客１）
うおっ 火神 速え！！
Kagami's fast!
He can't catch up!
（高尾(たかお)）追いつけない！？
（日向）いくら速いっつっても
ドリブルしてて火神より！？
I know he's fast, but how can he be faster than Kagami while dribbling?
I'm not giving up!
（火神）諦めてたまるか！
うおぁああああ！！
Impossible...
（伊月）そんな…
火神がここまで
手も足も出ないのか！？
Is Kagami really this useless against him?
Against Kise...
黄瀬とやったときも—
緑間とやったときも—
And even against Midorima...
He stopped his opponents, no matter how strong they were.
どんな強敵にも
食らいついて止めてみせた
So we thought he could do it again,
（日向）だから今度も…
but we were naive.
けど 甘かった
（日向）こいつは止められない
He's unstoppable!
（審判）バスケットカウント
ワンスロー！
Basket counts! And one!
This isn't your basketball, is it?
（青峰）そうじゃねえだろ
テメエらのバスケは
The only one who can beat me is me.
オレに勝てるのはオレだけだ
テメエだけじゃ あらがえねえよ
You can't fight me on your own.
出て来いよ… テツ
Come on out, Tetsu.
Let's settle this.
決着をつけようぜ
（リコ）20点差…
覚悟を決めるしかないわね
We're 20 points behind.
We have to prepare ourselves.
黒子(くろこ)君
Kuroko...
I'm fine.
（黒子）大丈夫です
もう十分 休めました
I've had plenty of time to rest.
行ってきます
I'm going.
（青峰）見せてみろよ
新しい光と影の底力をよ
Show me the strength of the new light and shadow.
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
Seirin, member change!
（オフィシャル）
誠凛(せいりん) メンバーチェンジです
Kuroko...
黒子
わりぃ
Sorry.
オレ１人じゃ
想像以上にしんどいわ
It's even harder by myself than I imagined.
I'm sorry, I don't understand.
（黒子）すみません
意味が分からないんですけど
What?
最初から一緒に
戦うつもりだったじゃないですか
We always intended to fight him together, didn't we?
そんなに簡単に勝てたら
苦労はないです
If winning were so simple, it would be too easy.
うっせえな わあってるよ
Shut up. I know!
いくぞ
Let's go!
Yeah, bring it on.
ああ 来いよ
（さつき）テツ君…
Tetsu...
黒子っち…
Kurokocchi...
Please.
お願い…
（今吉(いまよし)）え！？
（若松(わかまつ)）ぐあ！！
That's the full court pass they used in the Shutoku game!
（今吉）あれは…
秀徳(しゅうとく)戦で見せた超長距離パス…！
Amazing! What was that pass?
（観客１）すげえ
なんだ あのパス！！
（観客２）けど 青峰も速い！！
But Aomine's fast too!
I knew you'd catch up.
（火神）知ってるよ
追いついてくるんだろ？
What's wrong, Kagami?
どうした 火神？
ずいぶんとナイスパスじゃねえか！
That was a pretty nice pass.
Please make this shot, Captain!
決めてくださ〜い
（降旗）キャプテ〜ン！
（日向）ああ！？
Of course!
きたぁ〜！！
He made it!
後半ついに初得点
Our first points of the second half!
Touou
Seirin
つか 祈ってんじゃねえぞ １年
Quit praying, first years.
（３人）ぎえっ！！
オレが打つときは
たたえる準備だけしとけや
When I'm shooting, get ready to celebrate!
He's already in clutch time!
（１年生たち）
クラッチタイム 入ってた！！
続けていくぞ！
Let's keep it up!
He's amazing.
（桜井(さくらい)）すごいや あの人
He knew it would go in the moment he shot.
今 打った瞬間 入るのが分かった
（諏佐(すさ)）ああ！
Crap! What am I, stupid?
（今吉）
アカン！ アホか ワシは…
I didn't notice him!
（諏佐）桃井(ももい)から聞いてたのに—
ちょっとカッとなると
すぐ いること忘れちまう！
Get distracted for a second and you forget he's there!
うおおお 連続ゴール！
Two consecutive buckets!
It really is different with Kuroko!
黒子いると違うぜ！！
（青峰）やっぱ全然違(ちげ)えな
オマエが入るとよ
It really is completely different when you're playing.
You're still the same, Tetsu.
相変わらずだな テツ
中学のときと
ホント変わってねえわ
You really haven't changed since middle school.
ホント 全然…
Really. Not at all.
マジ ガッカリだわ
I'm disappointed.
まだそれで勝つつもりかよ？
オレに
You still think you can beat me?
I do.
そのつもりです
これが ボクのバスケです
This is my basketball.
Let's take back the game!
（伊月）
よし！ 一気に流れをとるぞ
Go!
行け！
Ignite Pass!
イグナイトパス
オマエのパスを
一番取ってきたのは—
Who do you think has caught your passes the most?
誰だと思ってんだよ？
No!
そんな…！！
Not even Takao could catch our trump card.
（リコ）高尾君でも取れなかった
切り札が…
Damn it!
くそっ！
ぬあ！
Seriously? He blew past three guys!
（観客１）マジかよ ３人抜き！？
（観客２）まさか１人で…
By himself? You gotta be kidding!
（リコ）５人抜き！？
He beat five guys.
そんな…
Impossible.
（青峰）悲しいぜ…
How sad.
You haven't changed at all since middle school.
最後の全中から
オマエは何も変わってない
You haven't improved.
同じってことは
成長してねえってことじゃねえか
Akashi was right after all.
やっぱ結局
赤司(あかし)が言ったとおりかよ…
Your basketball will never win.
オマエのバスケじゃ 勝てねえよ
Seirin
Touou
He shot while rolling!
（火神）ロール中に打った！？
メチャクチャだ
That's crazy!
Damn it!
くっそお！
Kagami?
（リコ）火神君？
足！？ なんで！？
His legs? Why?
They should be mostly healed, and I taped them up well.
ほとんど完治してる上に
テーピングもキッチリやった
They shouldn't get so bad this quickly.
そう簡単に悪化なんて…！
No, this is...
違う これは…
Seirin, member change.
（オフィシャル）
誠凛 メンバーチェンジです
火神君
Kagami...
Why again?
なんでまた！？
テーピングなら問題ねえっスよ
It's fine with the taping!
Just get on the bench.
（土田(つちだ)）いいから戻れよ
I'm fine!
大丈夫っスよ！
それにまだ試合…
こんなところで…
Besides, the game is still going.
I can't leave now.
Just get on the bench!
（リコ）いいから戻りなさい！！
I knew it.
（リコ）やっぱり…
He's been avoiding using his injured leg,
今まで痛めた足を
無理にかばいながら—
プレーしてしまったんだわ
and has been overcompensating with his other leg.
そのせいで
今度は逆の足に極端な負荷が…
この試合
もう出すわけにはいかない
I can't let him play anymore in this game,
or during the remaining two days of the championship league.
それどころか
決勝リーグ残り２日も…
Do you suppose the game will be over soon, Momoi?
（原澤(はらさわ)）いよいよ 決まりですかね
桃井さん
彼の対策もあったんでしょう？
Don't you have a strategy we can use against him?
どうします？
What shall we do?
いえ もう必要ない… と思います
No, it shouldn't be necessary anymore.
Hey, he's crazy.
（若松）
おいおい すんげえな あいつ
Huh?
（若松）人でも殺すんか？
Is he going to kill someone?
What?
（若松）今まで
青峰とやったヤツはみんな—
Everyone who has played against Aomine so far
才能の差に諦めるか
ぼう然とするか—
has given up or stood there stunned once they see how much better he is.
Either way, they lost their will.
どっちにしろ意気消沈って
感じだったんだけど—
But even after losing this badly,
and even more than before,
あいつはあんだけやられてなお
つか 今まで以上に—
he's radiating rage.
ほとばしってんぞ 怒りが
あんなヤツ 初めて見たわ
I've never seen anyone like him.
（日向）落ちる！
It'll miss!
He forced me to shoot!
打たされただけだ…
Our defense can't stop Aomine,
ディフェンスは
青峰を止められない上に—
オフェンスは桃井のせいで
全部読まれてる！
and they already know what we're going to do on offense because of Momoi!
This game is over.
（観客１）終わったな…
（観客２）さっきからもう一方的だ
見てらんねえわ
It's been one-sided for a while.
I can't watch this anymore.
Touou
Seirin
No matter what they do now, they can't win.
（観客１）
もう どうあがいても 無理だ…
We're 40 points behind.
（日向）40点差…
くっ！ マジで手も足も出ねえ
There's nothing we can do.
黒子も とっくに限界だ
Kuroko has already passed his limit too.
なら むしろコガに代えたほうが
いいんじゃねえのか？
Wouldn't it be better to sub him out for Koganei?
This was quicker than I expected.
思ったより早かったな
もう決まりだろ
It's already decided.
自慢のパスも通じず
体力も尽き—
Your special pass didn't work,
you're out of stamina,
オマエの光だった火神もいない
and your light is gone.
Your misdirection stopped working a while ago.
ミスディレクションも
とっくに切れた
Now you're worse than the average player.
もはや 並みのプレーヤー以下だ
バスケに一発逆転はねえよ
There's no such thing as a quick comeback in basketball.
オレの勝ちだ テツ
I win, Tetsu.
It's not over yet.
（黒子）まだ 終わってません
The possibility of victory is only 0% when all the players give up.
可能性がゼロになるとすれば
それは諦めたときです
どんなに無意味と思われても—
No matter how impossible it may seem,
I refuse to make it 0% myself.
自分からゼロにするのだけは
嫌なんです
That is why I will never give up!
だから 諦めるのは絶対 嫌だ！
Sheesh, we can't sub him out now.
（日向）
ったく そりゃ代えらんねえわ
We can't let a first year kid have more determination than us.
１年坊主のやる気に—
オレらが負けるわけには
いかねえよな
Sad...
（１年生たち）ドヨ〜ン
Hey, bench!
こら ベンチ お通夜か もっと…
Show some spirit! Let's go!
Keep your voices up until the end!
（小金井(こがねい)）声出せ！ 最後まで！
中の選手が諦めてねえんだぞ
The guys on the court haven't given up yet!
You can't sit here quietly!
黙ってて どうする？
Yeah!
（１年生たち）はいっ！
Defense, defense, defense!
（誠凛部員たち）
ディーフェンス！
Let's close the gap one bucket at a time.
とにかく１本ずつ縮めるぞ
走れよ 最後まで
Keep running until the very end.
フッ 当たり前だろう
Of course.
I'll acknowledge one thing.
１つだけ認めてやるわ
その 諦めの悪さだけは
You don't give up easily.
Running into the middle of that exciting stage...
Continually breakthrough your limits.
We have dreams, we're fond of legends, everybody in the ring.
Don't hesitate, into the future, JUMP!
They all say they haven't fallen after they have.
It's scary aiming at coming back from the dead but
if the road is still blocked
after I've crossed all the barriers,
I need to realize I'm not alone.
Slam it! We have to set the rim on fire!
Let's combine our power and our minds.
We don't need any excuses.
Gotta dream, exceed your limits, and war.
I need to face up to my common sense,
which I know all too well,
and bury my loneliness.
Let's fly now.
Get my stage!
Let's try now.
Next my stage!
Let's fly now.
No one gave up.
（リコ）誰一人 諦めず
全員が最後まで戦った
They all fought until the end.
But the difference in our scores only widened.
それでも点差は開き続けた
涙は出なかった
No one shed a single tear.
That day, we were...
（リコ）その日 私たちは…
Seirin
（リコ）それほど圧倒的に—
completely and totally...
Touou
負けた
destroyed.
Honnouteki naru situation
An instinctive situation,
tatakau imi o sagasu kono imitation
searching for a reason to fight this imitation.
Kurayami kara koboreru raito
Use the light that seeps from the darkness,
torawareta yourself kowase
and break free from your imprisonment.
Jiyuu ukeirete wa mogaite kuratte fuantei
Accept your freedom and struggle through your insecurities.
Kodou ga boku o tsukiage spy kidottenda
The pulsation throws me for a loop and I begin to spy.
Bring back the Catalyst "a simple way to best"
Bring back the Catalyst "a simple way to best."
And Rhythm like this never ends
And Rhythm like this never ends.
Sometimes your voice reached to me
Sometimes your voice reached to me,
Because I don't want to face the fate
because I dont want to face the fate.
Tobi tachitaku naru tte?
You say you wanna jump back up?
Katarurizumu oboete ndarou
You remember the catal rhythm, don't you?
Mune ni hibiku akirame no kako e
To the past resounding resignation in your chest,
Sabita sukoaboodo mitai ni
like a rusty scoreboard,
kimi mo koko de furuete ndarou?
you're shaking, aren't you?
Toriaezu wa mayoi no nai mirai e
For now, confidently head into the future.
Zanzou demo ii nda
Even if it's just a fragment of yourself.
Future aspect
Next Episode
Furihata here!
（降旗）降旗です
今日から練習メニュー３倍
Starting today, we'll practice three times as much!
（河原）河原です
オレたちも負けてらんないぞ
Kawahara here! We won't lose!
（福田）福田です
オレらは なんで名乗ってんの？
Fukuda here!
What are we doing here anyway?
（降旗）あっ つい…
It just happened.
つうか さっきからあそこで
あめ食べてる人… 誰？
So, who's the guy who's been standing there eating candy?
Episode 19
On to a New Challenge
Huh?